Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records 5084
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records
1933-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
5084
1.5 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Documents of the Switchmen's Union of North America, including expired insurance policies, deeds, bonds, blueprints, legal opinions, and correspondence.
5513792
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 21, 2014
EAD encoding:
Elizabeth Parker, March 20, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Switchmen's Union of North America is among the older of the railway brotherhoods. Beginning in 1877 with the formation of a local Switchmen's organization in Chicago, the movement became national when the Switchmen's Mutual Aid Association of North America held its first meeting nine years later.
This association was destroyed, as a result of a disastrous lockout by the Chicago Northwestern and the 1888 strike against the Chicago, Burlington and Quincy which had equally unfortunate results. Building on what was left of the S.M.A.A., several lodges met in Kansas City in October of 1854 and formed the Switchmen's Union of North America.
By the time of its merger into the United Transportation Union in 1969, the single Chicago labor organization of 1877 had grown to international status with 275 lodges in the United States and Canada having a combined membership of 12,000.
CHRONOLOGY
1877 Switchmen's Mutual Aid Association of North America organized
1886 Switchmen's Association organized
1889 Switchmen's Association affiliated with the Supreme Council of United Orders of Railway Employees
1894 Switchmen's Association dissolved in July
Switchmen's Union of North America organized on October 13
1906 Switchmen's Union of North America affiliated with the American Federation of Labor
1926 Switchmen's Union of North America becomes charter member of the Railway Labor Executives Association
1935 Switchmen's Union of North America affiliated with the Canadian Labor Congress
1969 Switchmen's Union of North America joined with the B.R.T., B.L.F. and E., and O.R.C.B. to form the United Transportation Union.
Scope and Contents
Includes expired insurance policies, deeds, bonds, blue prints, one folder entitled "Legal Opinions" on Resolution #22-1930, Convention and Resolution #4-1920 Strike."; notebook entitled "Corresp-Unification" Suwa D. Collins
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5034: Switchmen's Union of North America Records 5034 MB: Switchmen's Union of North America Memorabilia 5034 P: Switchmen's Union of North America Photographs 5405 mf: Switchmen's Union of North America Constitutions on Microfilm 5406 mf: Switchmen's Union of North America Arbitration on Microfilm 5447: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Unification Minutes and Convention Proceedings 5556: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records 5556 AV: Switchmen's Union of North America Audio-Visual Materials 5590: Switchmen's Union of North America Lake Shore Lodge 55 Membership Registers 5613: Switchmen's Union of North America Oakland Lodge 158 Meeting Minutes 5630: W.B. Meyers Papers
Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States; Railroads; Switchmen's Union of North America; United Transportation Union
5513792
- Application for and Certificate of Incorporation, 1901-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence and Minutes, SUNA, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Dan Collins, SUNA, Correspondence, Unification, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Legal Opinions on Resolution 22-1930 Convention, Resolution 4-1920 Strike, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Certificate of Insurance, Safety Deposit Box, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Sales Contract, Switchmen's Union of North America, 1920-1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Blue Print, Other Papers, 1920-1926 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Workmen's Compensation Policy No. 15C 46013, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Deed 31 North Street, 39 North Street, 3 Linwood, 1886-1937 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Owners', Landlords' and Tenants' Liability Policy, 1927-1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Insurance Policies, 1953-1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Nationwide Mutual Insurance Company Policies, 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Aetna Life and Casualty, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Workmen's Compensation Insurance, 1915-1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Workmen's Compensation and Lease, 1963-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Fire Policy, Master Policy Labor Organization Board, 1933-1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Internal Revenue Service, Ruling, 1936-1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Recommendations and Directives, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- John F. Kennedy Voting Correspondence, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Scope and Contents
  August 30 1960